当我一直在用大型语言模型构建应用程序时
When I've been building applications with large language models
我想我从来没有在第一次尝试时
I don't think I've ever come to the prompt that I ended up
就把提示词用对
using in the final application on my first attempt
因为这并不是最重要的
And this isn't what matters
只要你有一个好的迭代过程，能让你的提示语变得更好
As long as you have a good process to iteratively make your prompt better
那么你就能找到一些
then you'll be able to come to something that
对任务实现效果较好的提示词
works well for the task you want to achieve
你可能听我说过，当我训练一个机器学习模型时
You may have heard me say that when I train a machine learning model
它几乎从来没有第一次就成功过
it almost never works the first time
事实上，我很惊讶我训练的第一个模型能起作用
In fact, I'm very surprised that the first model I trained works
我认为我们在使用提示时，它第一次工作的几率可能会高一点
I think we're prompting, the odds of it working the first time is maybe a little bit
但正如她所说
higher but as she's saying
第一次提示是否有效并不重要
doesn't matter if the first prompt works
最重要的是获得提示的过程对你的应用有用
what matters most is the process for getting to prompts that works for your application
因此，让我们跳进代码，让我向你展示
So with that, let's jump into the code and let me show you
一些框架来思考如何迭代开发一个提示
some frameworks to think about how to iteratively develop a prompt
好的。如果你以前和我一起上过机器学习课
All right. So if you've taken a machine learning class with me
你可能见过我用一张图说，在机器学习开发中
before you may have seen me use a diagram saying that with machine learning development
你经常有一个想法，然后实现它
you often have an idea and then implement it
所以写代码，获取数据
So write the code, get the data
训练你的模型，这就给了你一个实验性的结果
train your model and that gives you an experimental result
然后你就可以看一下这个输出
And you can then look at that output
也许做错误分析
maybe do error analysis
找出它在什么地方起作用或不起作用
figure out where it's working or not working
然后甚至可能改变你的想法
and then maybe even change your idea of
你想解决什么问题或如何处理它
exactly what problem you want to solve or how to approach it
然后改变实施方案
And then change implementation and run
运行另一个实验等等，如此反复
another experiment and so on and iterate over and
来得到 一个有效的机器学习模型
over to get to an effective machine learning model
如果你对机器学习不熟悉
If you're not familiar with machine learning
没见过这张图，不用担心
haven't seen this diagram before, don't worry about it
对于本演讲的其余部分来说，并不那么重要
Not that important for the rest of this presentation
但是当你在写提示，使用LLM开发一个应用程序时
But when you are writing prompts to develop an application using an LLM
这个过程可以说是非常相似的
the process can be quite similar
你有一个关于你想做什么的想法
where you have an idea for what you want to do
你想完成的任务
the task you want to complete
然后你就可以初步尝试编写
and you can then take a first attempt at writing
希望能有一个清晰而具体的提示
a prompt that hopefully is clear and specific
如果合适的话
and maybe if appropriate
给予系统思考的时间
gives the system time to think
然后你可以运行它，看看你得到什么结果
And then you can run it and see what result you get
如果第一次的效果不够好
And if it doesn't work well enough the first time
那么，就需要反复的过程来弄清楚为什么指令
then the iterative process of figuring out why the instructions
例如，为什么指令不够清楚，或者为什么它
for example, were not clear enough or why it
为什么没有给算法足够的时间来思考
didn't give the algorithm enough time to think
这样你就可以完善这个想法了
allows you to refine the idea
完善提示，以此类推
refine the prompt, and so on
并在此基础上进行多次循环
and to go around this loop multiple times
直到你最终得到一个适用于你的应用的提示
until you end up with a prompt that works for your application
这也是为什么我个人没有那么多关注
This too is why I personally have not paid as much attention to
网上那些说有30个完美提示词的文章，因为我认为
the Internet articles that say 30 perfect prompts because I think
可能没有一个完美的提示适用于世间万物
there probably isn't a perfect prompt for everything under the sun
更重要的是，你要有一个过程，用于
It's more important that you have a process for
为你的特定应用挖掘出一个好的提示
developing a good prompt for your specific application
因此，让我们一起看下一个代码中的例子
So let's look at an example together in code
前面的视频中你所看到的初始代码
I have here the starter code that you saw in
已导入了openai和os
the previous videos have been import openai and port is
这里我们得到了OpenAI的API密钥
Here we get the OpenAI API key
这也是你上次看到的那个辅助函数
and this is the same helper function that you saw as last time
在这个视频中，我将使用这个例子
And I'm going to use as the running example in this video
为一张椅子写一份信息表
the task of summarizing a fact sheet for a chair
所以让我把它粘贴在这里
So let me just paste that in here
你可以选择随时暂停视频
and feel free to pause the video and read
在左边的Notebook上仔细地阅读这些代码
this more carefully in the notebook on the left if you want
但这里是一份椅子情况说明，上面写着
But here's a fact sheet for a chair with a description saying it's part of
它的灵感来自于一个华丽中世纪家族，等等
a beautiful family of mid-century inspired and so on
谈到了结构
talks about the construction
有尺寸，椅子的选择
has the dimensions, options for the chair
材料等等。它来自意大利
materials, and so on. It comes from Italy
因此，假设你想拿着这份概况介绍，帮助营销团队
So let's say you want to take this fact sheet and help
为在线零售网站编写一份描述
a marketing team write a description for an online retail website
让我快速运行这三个
Let me just quickly run these three
然后我们会有如下的提示
and then we'll come up with a prompt as follows
我就把这个粘贴进去
I'll just paste this in
所以我的提示是在这里说
So my prompt here says
你的任务是基于一份技术性的信息表
your task is to help a marketing team create
帮助一个营销团队，为零售网站
a description for a retail website or product based on a techno fact sheet
写一个产品描述，等等
write a product description, and so on
所以这是我第一次尝试向大语言模型解释任务
So this is my first attempt to explain the task to the large language model
因此，让我点击Shift Enter
So let me hit Shift Enter
而这需要几秒钟的时间来运行
and this takes a few seconds to run
然后我们得到这个结果
and we get this result
看起来它已经完成了一个很好的描述工作
It looks like it's done a nice job writing a description
介绍一个令人惊叹的中世纪风格的办公椅
introducing a stunning mid-century inspired office chair
完美的补充，等等
perfect addition, and so on
但是，当我看到这个时
But when I look at this, I go
发现这内容是真的长
boy, this is really long
它做得很好，正是我要求它做的
It's done a nice job doing exactly what I asked it to
这就是从技术概况表开始，写一个产品描述
which is start from the technical fact sheet and write a product description
但是，当我看到这个时，我就会说
But when I look at this, I go
内容有点长，也许我们希望它能短一点
this is long, maybe we want it to be a little bit shorter
所以我有一个想法
So I had an idea
我写了一个提示，得到了一个结果
I wrote a prompt, got a result
我对它不是那么满意，因为它太长了
I'm not that happy with it because it's too long
因此，我将让提示更清晰
So I will then clarify my prompt
嗯，并说，最多使用50个字，以尝试提供
um, and say, use at most 50 words to try to give
更好地指导所需的长度，然后我们再运行一次
better guidance on the desired length of this and let's run it again
好的。这实际上看起来是一个更好的简短描述，呃
Okay. This actually looks like a much nicer short description of, uh
介绍一个中世纪风格的办公椅的产品，诸如此类
the product introducing a mid-century inspired office chair, and so on
5个轮子支撑，对
5-wheel base, yeah
既时尚又实用
both stylish and practical
不错。嗯，让我再检查一下这个的长度是多少
Not bad. Um, and let me double-check the length that this is
所以我打算把答复，拆开来
So I'm going to take the response, split it
根据空间的位置
according to where the space is
然后，你知道，打印出长度
and then, you know, print out the length
所以它是52个字
So it's 52 words
这其实还不错
It's actually not bad
嗯，这大语言模型还不错
Um, large language models are okay
但在遵循关于非常精确的字数的指示方面，效果就不是那么好
but not that great at following instructions about a very precise word count
但这实际上还不错
But this is actually not bad
有时它会打印出60或65个单词长度的内容
Sometimes it will print out something with 60 or 65 and so on words
但这是在合理范围内的
but it's kind of within reason
你可以尝试做的一些事情是
Some of the things you could try to do would be
嗯，就是说，最多使用三个句子
um, to say, use at most three sentences
让我再试一次
Let me run that again
但这些都是不同的方式来告诉
But these are different ways to tell
这些是告诉大型语言模型你想要的输出的长度的不同方法
the large language model what's the length of the output that you want
所以这是1、2、3
So this is 1, 2, 3
我数了一下有三个句子
I count three sentences
看起来我做得很好
It looks like I did a pretty good job
嗯，然后我也看到人们有时会做一些事情，比如
Um, and then I've also seen people sometimes do things like
呃，我不知道，最多使用280个字符
uh, I don't know, use at most 280 characters
大语言模型，因为它们解释文本的方式
Large language models, because of the way they interpret text
是使用一种叫做标记器的东西
using something called a tokenizer
这我就不说了
which I won't talk about
但是，嗯，他们在计算字符方面往往很一般
But, um, they tend to be so-so at counting characters
但是让我们看看，281个字符
But let's see, 281 characters
这实际上是出乎意料的接近
It's actually surprisingly close
通常情况下，一个大语言模型是无法达到这么接近的
Usually a large language model is- doesn't get it quite this close
但这些是不同的方法
But these are different ways
他们可以尝试控制你得到的输出的长度
They can play with to try to control the length of the output that you get
但是，让我把它切换回最多使用50个词
But let me just switch it back to use at most 50 words
这就是我们刚才的结果
And there's that result that we had just now
当我们继续为我们的网站完善这个文本时
As we continue to refine this text for our websites
我们可能会决定，孩子
we might decide that, boy
这个网站并不是直接面向消费者销售的
this website isn't selling direct to consumers
实际上是要把家具卖给
is actually intended to sell furniture to
家具零售商，他们会对以下方面更感兴趣
furniture retailers that would be more interested in
椅子的技术细节和椅子的材料
the technical details of the chair and the materials of the chair
在这种情况下，你可以拿着这个提示说
In that case, you can take this prompt and say
我想修改这个提示，让它对技术细节更加精确
I want to modify this prompt to get it to be more precise about the technical details
所以让我继续修改这个提示
So let me keep on modifying this prompt
而我要说的是，这个描述是为家具零售商准备的
And I'm going to say, this description is intended for furniture retailers
所以应该更偏向技术，专注于材料
so should be technical and focus on materials
产品和构造
products and constructed from
让我们运行这个
Let's run that
让我们看看
And let's see
还不错，你知道
Not bad, says, you know
涂层铝基和气动椅，高质量的材料
coated aluminum base and pneumatic chair, high quality materials
因此，通过改变提示
So by changing the prompt
你可以让它更专注于特定内容
you can get it to focus more on specific characters
在你想要的特定特征上
on specific characteristics you wanted to
而当我看这个的时候
And when I look at this
我可能会决定在描述的最后
I might decide at the end of the description
我也想包括产品的ID
I also wanted to include the product IDs
所以这把椅子的两个产品
So the two offerings of this chair
SWC 110，SWC 100
SWC 110, SWC 100
因此，也许我可以进一步改进这个提示
So maybe I can further improve this prompt
并让它给我产品的ID
And to get it to give me the product IDs
我可以在描述的末尾添加这个指令
I can add this instruction at the end of the description
在技术规范中，用7个字符来描述每一个产品ID
include every seven character product ID in the technical specification
然后让我们运行它，看看会发生什么
And let's run it and see what happens
于是它说，介绍你的行政部门的文件办公椅
And so it says, introduce your administration's file office chair
外壳颜色，谈到塑料涂层，铝制底座
shell colors, talks about plastic coating, aluminum base
实用性，一些选项
practical, some options
谈到了两个产品ID
talks about the two product IDs
所以这看起来很不错
So this looks pretty good
而你刚才看到的是一个简短的迭代例子
And what you've just seen is a short example of the iterative
提示开发的一个简短例子，许多开发者都会经历
prompt development that many developers will go through
而我认为一个准则是
And I think a guideline is
在上一个视频中，你看到Isa分享了一些最佳做法
in the last video, you saw Isa share a number of best practices
因此，我通常所做的是将这样的最佳实践铭记在心
And so what I usually do is keep best practices like that in mind
清楚和具体，如果有必要的话
be clear and specific, and if necessary
给予模型思考的时间
give the model time to think
考虑到这些，经常在写提示时进行第一次尝试是值得的
With those in mind, it's worthwhile to often take a first attempt at writing a prompt
看看会发生什么，然后再从那里反复完善提示，以获得
see what happens, and then go from there to iteratively refine the prompt to get
越来越接近你需要的结果
closer and closer to the results that you need
因此，你可能会看到在各种项目中使用的许多成功的提示语
And so a lot of the successful prompts that you may see used in various programs
是通过这样的迭代过程得出的
was arrived at at an iterative process like this
为了好玩，让我给你看一个更复杂的提示的例子，它可以
Just for fun, let me show you an example of a even more complex prompt that might
让你感受一下ChatGPT的功能
give you a sense of what ChatGPT can do
我只是在这里添加了一些额外的指令
which is I've just added a few extra instructions here
在描述之后，包括一个给出产品尺寸的表格
After the description, include a table that gives the product dimensions
然后，把所有东西都格式化为HTML
and then, you know, format everything as HTML
所以，让我们再次运行
So let's run that
在实践中，你最终会得到这样的提示
And in practice, you would end up with a prompt like this
其实只有在多次反复之后才会出现
really only after multiple iterations
我想我不知道有谁会在第一次就写出这样准确的提示语
I don't think I know anyone that would write this exact prompt the first time
他们试图让系统处理一个信息表
they were trying to get the system to process a fact sheet
因此，这实际上输出了一堆HTML
And so this actually outputs a bunch of HTML
让我们显示一下HTML，看看这是否是有效的HTML，看看这是否有效
Let's display the HTML to see if this is even valid HTML and see if this works
我不知道它是否能工作，但让我们看看
And I don't actually know it's going to work, but let's see
哦，太好了。不错
Oh, cool. All right
看来它成功渲染了
Looks like it rendered
所以它有一个非常漂亮的椅子描述
So it has this really nice looking description of a chair
结构、材料、产品尺寸
construction, materials, product dimensions
哦，看来我漏掉了最多使用50个字的说明
Oh, it looks like I left out the use at most 50 words instruction
所以这有点长，但如果你想要调整的话
So this is a little bit long, but if you want that, you know
你可以随意暂停视频
you can even feel free to pause the video
告诉它要更简洁，并重新生成这个，看看你得到什么结果
tell it to be more succinct and regenerate this and see what results you get
因此，我希望你能从这个视频中得到启发，即
So I hope you take away from this video that
提示开发是一个迭代的过程
prompt development is an iterative process
尝试一些东西，看看它如何还不能完全满足你的要求
Try something, see how it does not yet fulfill exactly what you want
然后再考虑如何更清楚地描述指示
and then think about how to clarify your instructions
或者在某些情况下，考虑如何给它更多的空间来思考
or in some cases, think about how to give it more space to think
以使它更接近于提供你想要的结果
to get it closer to delivering the results that you want
我认为成为一个有效的提示工程师的关键在于
And I think the key to being an effective prompt engineer
他并不在于知道完美的提示
isn't so much about knowing the perfect prompt
但了解如何用一个更好过程来开发提示
it's about having a good process to develop
让应用能够更加高效
prompts that are effective for your application
在这段视频中，我只用一个例子说明了开发提示语
And in this video, I illustrated developing a prompt using just one example
对于更复杂的应用
For more sophisticated applications
有时你会有多个例子
sometimes you will have multiple examples
例如，一个有10个或甚至50个或100个信息表的列表
say a list of 10 or even 50 or 100 fact sheets
迭代开发一个提示，并根据大量的案例对其进行评估
and iteratively develop a prompt and evaluate it against a large set of cases
但是对于大多数应用的早期开发来说
But for the early development of most applications
我看到许多人在开发它时就像我一样只用一个例子
I see many people developing it sort of the way I am with just one example
但是，对于更成熟的应用来说
But then for more mature applications
有时，用更多的例子来评估提示可能是有用的
sometimes it could be useful to evaluate prompts against a larger set of examples
例如，在几十张信息表上测试不同的提示，以了解
such as to test different prompts on dozens of fact sheets to see
在多个信息表上的平均或最坏情况下的表现如何
how is average or worst case performances on multiple fact sheets
但通常情况下，只有当一个应用程序比较成熟时，你才会这样做
But usually, you end up doing that only when an application is more mature
而且你必须有这些指标来推动
and you have to have those metrics to drive
你必须有这些指标来推动最后几步的增量的迅速改进
that incremental last few steps of prompt improvement
因此，请大家玩一玩
So with that, please do play with
Jupyter Notebook的例子，尝试一下
the Jupyter Code notebook examples and try out
不同的变化，看看你得到了什么结果
different variations and see what results you get
当你完成后，让我们继续看下一个视频
And when you're done, let's go on to the next video
我们将讨论软件应用中的一个非常普遍的用途
where we'll talk about one very common use of
大语言模型在软件应用中的一个非常普遍的用途
large language models in software applications
这就是对文本进行总结
which is to summarize text
所以，当你准备好了，让我们继续看下一个视频
So when you're ready, let's go on to the next video